Guide to the Herndon Dowling Herpetological Collection MS 059
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Species Files (with non-digitized drawings)
  - Cryptolycus, undated (Box 09, Folder 0369)
    Folder notes: CAE BOE BOE LYC, Other markings:
    34023001515255
  - Dendrolycus, undated (Box 09, Folder 0370)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM LAM LYC, Other markings: RS SE CO 956DEN08
    34023001515263
  - Hormonatus Hallowell, 1971 (Box 09, Folder 0371)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM LAM LYC, Other markings: 857HOR07
    34023001515131
  - Lycophidion, 1971 (Box 09, Folder 0372)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM LAM LYC, Other markings: 843LYC08
    34023001515149
  - Amblyodipsas, 1970 (Box 09, Folder 0373)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB E, Other markings: RS SE CO 856AMB09
    34023001515156
  - Brachyophis, undated (Box 09, Folder 0374)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB E, Other markings: RS SE CO 888BRA08
    34023001515164
  - Chilorhinophis, undated (Box 09, Folder 0375)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB E, Other markings:
    34023001515172
  - Elapotinus, undated (Box 09, Folder 0376)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB E, Other markings: RS SE CO 862ELA07
    34023001515198
  - Hypoptophis, undated (Box 09, Folder 0377)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB E, Other markings: RS SE CO 908HYP08
    34023001515180
  - Macrelaps, 1971 (Box 09, Folder 0378)
    34023001515206
  - Poecilopholis, 1971 (Box 09, Folder 0379)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB E, Other markings: RS SE CO 903POE10
    34023001515321
  - Polemon, 1972 (Box 09, Folder 0380)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR AMB, Other markings:
    34023001515313
  - Xenocalamus, undated (Box 10, Folder 0381)
    34023001515305
  - Aparallactus, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 0382)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR APA E, Other markings: RS SE CO 849APA09
    34023001515297
  - Atractaspis, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 0383)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR ATR E, Other markings: RS SE CO 849ATR08
    34023001515289
  - Micrelaps, undated (Box 10, Folder 0384)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR ATR ? E, Other markings: RS SE CO 879MIC06
    34023001515271
  - Amlorhinus, undated (Box 10, Folder 0385)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR ??? E, Other markings: RS SE CO 847AMP08
    34023001515339
  - Duberria, undated (Box 10, Folder 0386)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ATR PSD E, Other markings: RS SE CO 826DUB05
    34023001515347
  - Psammophiinas, undated (Box 10, Folder 0387)
    Folder notes: CAE BOA ATR, Other markings:
    34023001515404
  - Dipsina, undated (Box 10, Folder 0388)
    Folder notes: CAE BOA ATR PSA, Other markings:
    34023001515396
  - Dromophis, undated (Box 10, Folder 0389)
    34023001515388
  - Hemirhagerrhis, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 0390)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 893HEM11
    34023001515370
  - Malpolon, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 0391)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 826MAL05
    34023001515354
  - Nimophis, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 0392)
    Folder notes: MAD, Other markings: RS SE CO 868MIM05
    34023001515362
  - Psammophis, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 0393)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 826PSA07
    34023001516204
  - Psammophylax, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 0394)
    34023001516246
  - Rhamphiophis, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 0395)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 854RHA09
    34023001516212
  - Acanthophis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0396)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 803ACA08
    34023001516220
  - Aspidelaps, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0397)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 848ASP07
    34023001516238
  - Aspidomorphus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0398)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 843ASP10
    34023001516113
  - Boulengerina, undated (Box 10, Folder 0399)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 886BOU09
    34023001516196
  - Bungarus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0400)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 803BUN05
    34023001516162
  - Cacophis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0401)
    Folder notes: CAE ELA ELA ACA - A, Other markings:
    34023001516170
  - Calliophis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0402)
    34023001516188
  - Demansia, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0403)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 842DEM05
    34023001516121
  - Dendroaspis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0404)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 848DEN08
    34023001516139
  - Denisonia, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0405)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 869DEN06
    34023001516154
  - Echiopsis, undated (Box 10, Folder 0406)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL
    34023001516147
  - Elapsoidea, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0407)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 866ELA07
    34023001516386
  - Furina, undated (Box 10, Folder 0408)
    34023001516378
  - Glyphodon, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0409)
    34023001516360
  - Hemachatus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0410)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 822HEM07
    34023001516345
  - Homoroselaps, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0411)
    34023001516352
  - Hoplocephalus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0412)
    34023001516253
  - Leptomicrurus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0413)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 937LEP10
    34023001516295
  - Maticora, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0414)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 834MAT05
    34023001516287
  - Micropechis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0415)
    Folder notes: Elpaidae! Possible Acaroc Xenodermatid?, Other markings: RS SE EL EL 896MIC08
    34023001516279
  - Micruroides, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0416)
    34023001516261
  - Micrurus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0417)
    34023001516303
  - Naja, undated (Box 10, Folder 0418)
    34023001516311
  - Neelaps, undated (Box 10, Folder 0419)
    Folder notes: ?= vermicella (sc.), Other markings:
    34023001516337
  - Notechis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0420)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 896NOT05
    34023001516329
  - Ogmodon, undated (Box 10, Folder 0421)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 865OGM04
    34023001516485
  - Ophiophagus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0422)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 864OPH08
    34023001516519
  - Oxyuranus, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0423)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 923OXY06
    34023001516501
  - Paranaja, undated (Box 10, Folder 0424)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 944PAR05
    34023001516493
  - Pseudechis, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0425)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 830PSE07
    34023001516477
  - Pseudohaje, undated (Box 10, Folder 0426)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 858PSE07
    34023001516469
  - Pseudonaja, undated (Box 10, Folder 0427)
    34023001516444
  - Salomonelaps, undated (Box 10, Folder 0428)
    34023001516451
  - Simoselaps, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0429)
    34023001516394
  - Suta, undated (Box 10, Folder 0430)
    34023001516428
  - Toxicocalamus, undated (Box 10, Folder 0431)
    34023001516410
  - Tropidechis, undated (Box 10, Folder 0432)
    34023001516402
  - Ultrocalamus, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 0433)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 913ULT09
    34023001516634
  - Vermicella, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 0434)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 858VER07
    34023001516642
  - Walterinnesia, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 0435)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL EL 887WAL10
    34023001516659
  - Laticauda, undated (Box 10, Folder 0436)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 786LAT06
    34023001516667
  - Hydrophiidae, undated (Box 11, Folder 0437)
    34023001516626
  - Hydrophiidae, undated (Box 11, Folder 0438)
    34023001516618
  - Acalyptophis, undated (Box 11, Folder 0439)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 896ACA09
    34023001516600
  - Aipysurus, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0440)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 804AIP06
    34023001516550
  - Astrotia, undated (Box 11, Folder 0441)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 865AST05
    34023001516576
  - Disteira, undated (Box 11, Folder 0442)
    34023001516568
  - Emydocephalus, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0443)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 869EMY10
    34023001516584
  - Enhydrina, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0444)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 849ENH06
    34023001516543
  - Hydrelaps, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 0445)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 896HYD06
    34023001516808
  - Hydrophis, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0446)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 802HYD06
    34023001516790
  - Kerilia, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0447)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 849KER04
    34023001516782
  - Lapemis, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0448)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 835LAP04
    34023001516766
  - Microcephalophis, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0449)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 834MIC13
    34023001516774
  - Pelamis, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0450)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 803PEL04
    34023001516717
  - Thalassophis, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0451)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 852THA09
    34023001516725
  - Praescutata, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0452)
    Folder notes: RS SE EL HY 921PRA08
    34023001516733
  - Venemous Snakes, undated (Box 11, Folder 0453)
    34023001516758
  - Agkistrodon, undated (Box 11, Folder 0454)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI CR 799AGK08
    34023001516741
  - Azemiops, undated (Box 11, Folder 0455)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 888AZE05
    34023001516683
  - Crotalinae, undated (Box 11, Folder 0456)
    34023001516675
  - Crotalidae, undated (Box 11, Folder 0457)
    34023001516691
  - Atropoides, undated (Box 11, Folder 0458)
    34023001516535
  - Bothriechis, undated (Box 11, Folder 0459)
    34023001516592
  - Bothriopsis, undated (Box 11, Folder 0460)
    34023001516436
  - Bothrops, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 0461)
    Folder notes: 1 of 2, Other markings: RS SE VI CR 824BOT05
    34023001516527
  - Bothrops, undated (Box 11, Folder 0462)
    Folder notes: 2 of 2, Other markings: RS SE VI CR 824BOT05
    34023001516709
  - Crotalus, undated (Box 11, Folder 0463)
    Folder notes: 1 of 3, Other markings: RS SE VI CR 758CRO05
    34023001515446
  - Crotalus, undated (Box 11, Folder 0464)
    Folder notes: 2 of 3, Other markings: RS SE VI CR 758CRO05
    34023001515438
  - Crotalus, undated (Box 11, Folder 0465)
    Folder notes: 3 of 3, Other markings: RS SE VI CR 758CRO05
    34023001515420
  - Deinaguistrodon, undated (Box 11, Folder 0466)
    34023001515412
  - Gloydius, undated (Box 11, Folder 0467)
    Folder notes: (Asian "Aguistrodon"), Other markings: VIP CRO
    34023001515453
  - Lachesis, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 0468)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI CR 803LAC05
    34023001515479
  - Ophryacus, Ovophis, Porthidium, undated (Box 11, Folder 0469)
    Folder notes: (NR Bathrops, NR Trimeresurces,, Other markings:
    34023001515461
  - Sistrurus, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 0470)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI CR 883SIS06
    34023001515487
  - Trimeresurus, undated (Box 11, Folder 0471)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI CR 804TRI09
    34023001515495
  - Viperidae, undated (Box 11, Folder 0472)
    34023001515503
  - Adenorhinos, undated (Box 11, Folder 0473)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 965ADE08
    34023001515511
  - Atherus, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 0474)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 862ATH04
    34023001515545
  - Bitis, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 0475)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 842BIT02
    34023001515537
  - Causus, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 0476)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 830CAU03
    34023001515529
  - Cerastes, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0477)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 768CER05
    34023001515552
  - Echis, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 0478)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 820ECH02
    34023001515560
  - Eristicophis, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 0479)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 897ERI09
    34023001515578
  - Pseudocerastes, undated (Box 12, Folder 0480)
    Folder notes: RS SE VI VI 896PSE11
    34023001515594
  - Russell's Viper, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 0481)
    34023001515586
  - Vipera, undated (Box 12, Folder 0482)
    Folder notes: 1 of 3, Other markings: RS SE VI VI 768VIP03
    34023001515602
  - Vipera, undated (Box 12, Folder 0483)
    Folder notes: 2 of 3, Other markings: RS SE VI VI 768VIP03
    34023001515628
  - Vipera, undated (Box 12, Folder 0484)
    Folder notes: 3 of 3, Other markings: RS SE VI VI 768VIP03
    34023001515610
  - Anomalepididae, undated (Box 12, Folder 0485)
    Folder notes: RS SE AO
    34023001515651
  - Anomalepis, undated (Box 12, Folder 0486)
    Folder notes: RS SE AO SCO TYP ANO --TM-TS
    34023001515636
  - Helminthophis, undated (Box 12, Folder 0487)
    Folder notes: RS SE AO SCO TYP ANO -- TC-TS
    34023001515644
  - Liotyphlops, undated (Box 12, Folder 0488)
    34023001515669
  - Typhlophis, undated (Box 12, Folder 0489)
    Folder notes: RS SE AO SCO TYP ANO -- S
    34023001515685
  - Typhlopidae, undated (Box 12, Folder 0490)
    Folder notes: RS SE TY
    34023001515677
  - Cyclotyphops, undated (Box 12, Folder 0491)
    Folder notes: SCO TYP TYP
    34023001515693
  - Ramphotyphlops, undated (Box 12, Folder 0492)
    Folder notes: RS SE TY 843RAM11 SCO TYP TYP -- A-O
    34023001515701
  - Typhlops, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 0493)
    Folder notes: RS SE TY 811TYP05 SCO TYP TYP -- W
    34023001515719
  - Xenotyphlops, undated (Box 12, Folder 0494)
    34023001515735
  - Leptotyphlopidae, undated (Box 12, Folder 0495)
    Folder notes: RS SE LE
    34023001515727
  - Leptotyphlops, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 0496)
    Folder notes: SCO LEP LEP -- T-E-P, Other markings: RS SE LE 843LEP10
    34023001515743
  - Rhinoleptus, undated (Box 12, Folder 0497)
    Folder notes: RS SE LE 970RHI08
    34023001515750
  - Boidae, undated (Box 12, Folder 0498)
    34023001515768
  - Calabaria, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 0499)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT CAL -- E, Other markings: RS SE BO 858CAL06
    34023001515776
  - Loxocemus, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0500)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT LOX -- TC-TM, Other markings: RS SE XE 861LOX06
    34023001515784
  - Xenopeltis, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0501)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT XEN -- O, Other markings: RS SE XE 827XEN07
    34023001515792
  - Anilidae, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0502)
    Folder notes: RS SE AN
    34023001515800
  - Anilius, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0503)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT ANI -- TS, Other markings: RS SE AN 816ANI04
    34023001515818
  - Pythonidae, undated (Box 12, Folder 0504)
    34023001515826
  - Boa and Python Hemipenis Drawings By O.G. Stull, undated (Box 12, Folder 0505)
    34023001515875
  - Pythons-reproduction, undated (Box 12, Folder 0506)
    34023001515867
  - [Pythons], undated (Box 12, Folder 0507)
    Folder notes: Hand written data., Other markings:
    34023001515859
  - [Pythons], 19601990s (Box 12, Folder 0508)
    Folder notes: Hand written data., Other markings: Dr. Dowling
    34023001515842
  - Aspidites, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0509)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT PYT --A, Other markings: RS SE BO 864ASP06
    34023001515834
  - Bothrochilus, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0510)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT PYT --A, Other markings: RS SE BO 843BOT09
    34023001515883
  - Chondropython, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0511)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT PYT --A, Other markings: RS SE BO 874CHO10
    34023001515891
  - Liasis, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 0512)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT PYT --A, Other markings: RS SE BO 842LIA03
    34023001515909
  - Morelia, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 0513)
    Folder notes: HEN PYT PYT --A, Other markings: RS SE BO 842MOR04
    34023001515917
  - Python, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 0514)
    Folder notes: HEP PYT PYT _EO, Other markings: RS SE BO 803PYT03 (may be additional drawings)
    34023001515925
  - Teretrurus, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0525)
    Folder notes: SCO LEP URO - O, Other markings: RS SE UR 886TER07
    34023001516048
  - Uropeltis, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0526)
    Folder notes: SCO LEP URO - O, Other markings: RS SE UR 829URO06
    34023001516006
  - Charina, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0528)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO ERY -NU, Other markings: RS SE BO 842CHA04
    34023001516022
  - Eryx, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0529)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO ERY -O, Other markings: RS SE BO 803ERY01
    34023001516014
  - Lichanura, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0530)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO ERY -NU NM, Other markings: RS SE BO 861LIC06
    34023001515990
  - Acranthropis, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0535)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI - IM, Other markings: RS SE BO 860ACR08
    34023001504796
  - Boa, undated (Box 13, Folder 0536)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TS -TM, Other markings: RS SE BO 758BOA00
    34023001504804
  - Candoia, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0537)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI - SS, Other markings: RS SE BO 842CAN04
    34023001504838
  - Corallus, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0538)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TS-TW-TC, Other markings: RS SE BO 803COR05
    34023001504820
  - Epicrates, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0539)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TW-TS, Other markings: RS SE BO 830EPI06
    34023001504812
  - Exiliboa, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0540)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TM, Other markings: RS SE BO BO 968EXI05
    34023001504861
  - Eunectes, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0541)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TS, Other markings: RS SE BO 830EUN05
    34023001504853
  - Sanzinia, undated (Box 13, Folder 0542)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -IM, Other markings: RS SE BO 849SAN05
    34023001504846
  - Ungaliophis, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0543)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TM -TS, Other markings: RS SE BO 882UNG09
    34023001504879
  - Xenoboa, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 0544)
    Folder notes: HEN BOO BOI -TS, Other markings: RS SE BO 953XEN04
    34023001504887
  - Trachyboa, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0545)
    Folder notes: CAE TRO TRO -TC (P) -TS, Other markings: RS SE BO 860TRA06
    34023001504895
  - Tropidophis, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0546)
    Folder notes: CAE TRO TRO -TS -TN, Other markings: RS SE BO 840TRO08
    34023001504903
  - Phyllorhynchus, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 0547)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 890PHY11
    34023001504630
  - Grayia, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 0549)
    Folder notes: CAE ACR XENODERM, Other markings: RS SE CO 858GRA03
    34023001504655
  - Chironius, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 0551)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 826CHI06
    34023001504671
  - Xenodermus, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 0553)
    Folder notes: CAE ACR XEN -OM, Other markings: RS SE CO 836XEN07
    34023001504697
  - Colubridae Elaphe, undated (Box 13, Folder 0554)
    Folder notes: 1 of 2, Other markings: Looseleaf note book
    34023001504705
  - Colubridae Elaphe, undated (Box 13, Folder 0555)
    Folder notes: 2 of 2, Other markings: Looseleaf note book
    34023001504358
- General Files
  These are materials that were in Dowling's file cabinets. Some contents of the file drawers may have been shifted and were not in the intended order upon accession to the WCSU Archives. These materials are only lightly processed and remain essentially in its original order but reboxed. Each box indicates the cabinet from which the materials eminated. The boxes have been assigned to some broad subseries classifications (Couse materials, Research - Background, Field Work, Alphabetical files, and Published materials + manuscripts).
  Conditions Governing Access
  There are financial and personal materials contained herein that warrant a limit to access. Researchers will need prior permission of the Archivist to review some of these materials.
  - Course Materials
    - Field Courses and Grants, undated (Box ms059_files_57)
      Bay 11, drawer 4
      1991 field trip, natural history vertebrae, Jamaica course, Jamaica budget, Jamaica special notes.
    - Field Courses and Grants, undated (Box ms059_files_58)
      Jamaica natural history, Jamaica anoles, Vertebrate Biology lecture.
    - Field Courses and Grants, undated (Box ms059_files_59)
      Bay 11 drawer 4
      NSF grant proposals, old grants, Herps: ID and info.
    - Field Courses and Grants, undated (Box ms059_files_60)
      NIH and NSF grant info and proposals, Genera of Reptiles
    - Field Courses and Grants, undated (Box ms059_files_61)
      Materials for NSF Grants, US Civil Service Commission, grant proposals, NYU grants, NYU sabatical leaves.
    - Field Courses and Grants, undated (Box ms059_files_62)
      Elaphe breeding, manuel for snake hunting in the South.
    - Personal-teaching, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_88)
      bay 13, drawer 3.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_89)
      bay 13 drawer 2.
      Alabama and misc research.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_90)
      bay 13, drawer 2 and 3.
      electrphoresis and university notes.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_91)
      Misc herpatology notes and evolution.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009
      misc herpatological materials, amphibians, universities.
  - Research - Background
    - Prodromus of a new classification of snakes, 1970s-1998 (Box ms059_files_01)
      This material is unprocessed and was in Bay 1, drawer 2 of Dowling's file cabinet. 1 Box.
      Contains the prodromus and supporting materials. Approximately 1 linear foot.
    - Classification Older Work, undated (Box ms059_files_02)
      Bay 1, drawer 3
      Contains notes and data, and drafts of 1995 prodromus.
    - Paleontology and Evolution, undated (Box ms059_files_03)
      Bay 2, drawer 2
      All articles and clippings.
    - Reproductive System Majpura, undated (Box ms059_files_06)
      Bay 3, drawer 2
      Evidence of mouse infestation; computer print outs with computer cards and article reprints.
    - Reproductive System Majpura, undated (Box ms059_files_06.1)
      evidence of mouse infestation
      includes a variety of snake reproductive system research articles and punch cards.
    - Drawing Reprints, 1941-1990 (Box ms059_files_07)
      bay 3, drawer 3
      Article clippings; in chronological order starting in 1941 going through 1990. Includes a copy of systematic herpatology: a synopsis of families in higher categories by Herndon Dowling and William Duellman 1978.
    - Specimen Numbers and Punchcards and Grant Proposals, undated (Box ms059_files_08)
      Bay 3, drawer 4
      From drawer marked taxes. Includes a book of specimen numbers, computer cards, and various NSF grant materials and paperwork.
    - Clippings, undated (Box ms059_files_21)
      Bay 7, drawer 4
      Includes journal and article clippings from a variety of topics.
    - Ecology, undated (Box ms059_files_30)
      Bay 8, drawer 4
      Includes files on: ecology, biodiversity, life history (snakes), phenology, predation, thermoregulation, "herp humor", social behavior.
    - Ecology, undated (Box ms059_files_31)
      Includes files on: reproduction, gestation, embryology, hybrids, captivity/maintenance, cage design, museums/zoos, regulation of reptiles and amphibians.
    - Ecology, undated (Box ms059_files_32)
      Inlcudes files on reptile disease, zoo cencus (bronx), snake mites, environmental impact, repellents, foreign dealers, reptiles in advertisements, salmonellosis, post mortum reports, insecticide use.
    - Morphology and Systems, undated (Box ms059_files_33)
      Bay 9, drawer 3
      Includes files on cytology, snake drawings, frogs, salamanders, non-snake karyotypes, lygaphils.
    - Morphology and Systems, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_34)
      bay 4, drawer 3
      includes files on: brooding and parental care, snake anatomy, snake karyology, snake heads, feeding mechanisms, snake scent glands.
    - Morphology and Systems, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_35)
      bay 9, drawer 3
      Includes files on skeletal system, skeletal prep, reproductive system, reproductive anatomy, reproductive behavior, lizards, hemipenis original drawings, muscular system, sensory system, muscles body, pigmentary system, sensory-ear, eye, sensory-tongue, skelton-limbs.
    - Morphology and Systems, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_36)
      teeth and fangs, snake skulls and maxillae, anatomy-vartebrae, snake vertebrae, anatomy-skull.
    - Venoms, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_37)
      bay 9, drawer 4
      venom and snakebite, venom studies, snakebite treatment, importation of venomous snakes, venemous snakes, Henry M. Parrish, snakebite, snake venom.
    - Venoms, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_38)
      snake venom action, venom yield and toxicity, snake venom medical uses, snake bite procedure (historical), venoms (other than snake), snakebite information, snakebite newspaper clippings.
    - Venoms, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_39)
      identification of venemous snakes, snakebites-reports and therapy, treatments of snakebites-experimental